자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
왜 그래? 네가 제일 좋아하는
아몬드랑 건포도잖니
What's your problem? It's your
favorite. Almonds and raisins.
그래, 먹지 마라
Fine, don't eat.
하지만, 경고하는데
이게 오늘 마지막인 줄 알아
But I'm warning you.
That's it for the rest of the day.
나중에 뭐라고 하기 없기다
Don't be complaining later.
이봐요, 진정해요
Hey, hey.
Come on.
제정신이 아니군요
당신 미쳤어요
You're crazy.
You know that? You're nuts.
조용히 해
쥐 죽은 듯이 있어라
Quiet.
Be as quiet as a you-know-what.
정말 미치겠네
난 도청 장치 안 했어요
This is so bogus.
I'm not wearing a wire.
돌아 서 / 몸수색은 당신이
받아야 할 것 같은데요
Turn around.
I should be frisking you, man.
그래? / 네
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- 왜 검사랑 얘기한 거지?
- 그 사람들이 나한테 왔다고요
- Why were you talking to the DA?
- They came to me.
- 난들 어쩌겠어요?
- 놈들 쪽으로 붙었나? / 아뇨
- What was I supposed to do?
- Did you roll over? / No.
- 난 아무 말도 안 했어요
- 배신을 한 거야? / 아니에요
- I didn't tell them anything.
- Did you roll over? / No.
맹세하는데 난 아무 말도
안 했어요. 날 잘 알잖아요
I swear to god. I didn't tell them
anything. You know me.
그래, 네놈을 잘 안다
그리고 넌 내 신경을 긁고 있지
Yeah, I know you,
And you're making me nervous.
나만 그렇게 느끼는 게 아니야
넌 모두에게 골칫거리야
You know what, not just me.
You're making everybody nervous.
이봐요, 이봐!
Hey, there's a man in there.
저쪽에서 누가 절 쫓아와요
저 사람이 누군가를 죽인 것 같아요
He was chasing me.
I think he killed someone.
여기 계세요. 우리가 살펴보죠
Stay back here.
We'll take a look.
MONK Season 4 Epi. 12
Mr. Monk and the Captain's Marriage
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
진현경(jhk8012@nate.com)
싱크편집
최자앵(ashaa@nate.com)
한글번역
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
한글교정
이미란(lmr0412@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/01/27
몽크
Monk.
나탈리 씨
이렇게 빨리 와 줘서 고마워요
Natalie.
Thanks for getting here so fast.
- 여긴 전자제품 가게가 아니잖아요
- 그래, 나도 아네
- This is not an appliance store.
- Yeah, I know.
전자제품 가게라고 하셨잖아요
You said it was an appliance store.
미안하네. 내가 거짓말했어
하지만, 폐품 처리장이라고 했으면
I'm sorry, I lied.
But if I'd told you
it was a junkyard, it would've taken
me 5 hours to get you down here.
자네가 오기까지 다섯 시간은
걸릴 것 같았거든
- 폐품 처리장이라니...
- 잠깐만요. 그럼 거짓말을 하신 거예요?
This is a junkyard.
W..wait, so you lied to us?
미안해요
워낙 중요한 사건이라서요
I'm sorry..
This is a big case.
방금 터진 사건이에요
한 20분밖에 안 됐죠
It just went down.
About 20 minutes ago.
간만에 따끈따끈한 범죄 현장이 생겼기에
빨리 오게 하려고 그런 겁니다
We've got a fresh crime
scene for once.
I wanted him here right away.
거짓말을 하셨다니 믿기지가 않네요
I can't believe you lied to us.
미안하다고 했잖아요
두 번이나요
Look, I said I'm sorry.
I think twice.
얼마나 더 사과를 해야 합니까?
How many times do I need
to apologize?
- 여섯 번요
- 6.
미안해요. 미안해요. 미안해요
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
이제 시작할까요?
Can we do this?
피해자는 조무래기 마약상이었어
The victim was a small time
drug dealer.
지미 바츠데일이란 친군데
별명은 치클릿이야
Jimmy Botsdale.
They called him Chicklet.
마이클 카르파프 밑에서 일했었어
He used to work for Michael Karpov.
조금 전에 그 사람에 관한
기사를 읽고 있었어요
Karpov, I was just reading
about that guy.
카르파프는 다음달에
범죄 공모 및 돈세탁 혐의로
Karpov is going on trial
next month for criminal conspiracy
재판을 받을 예정이야
나도 수사를 도왔었지
and money laundering.
I helped make the case.
치클릿은 카르파프에 대해
증언을 하기로 되어 있었어
Chicklet was supposed to
testify against him.
이 고철들 좀 봐요
Look at all this junk.
어딘가로 치워야 해요
They should get rid of it.
And put it somewhere.
그렇게 했잖아요, 몽크 씨
바로 여기 폐품 처리장으로요
Well, they did it, Mr. Monk.
They put it here. It's a junkyard.
- 그 말이 맞네요
- 계속 설명하겠네
- You can say that again.
- I'm gonna keep talking.
오늘 아침 누군가 치클릿을
이리 부른 다음 살해했어
Somebody lured Chicklet here
this morning and killed him.
하지만, 목격자가 있었네
노숙자인데 사건을 전부 목격했지
There was a witness however, a
homeless man. He saw the whole thing.
그 사람은 어디에 있는데요?
Well, where is he?
사라졌어요. 그 사람이 순찰차를
불러 세웠는데, 그리고는 없어졌죠
We lost him. He flagged down a patrol
car and then he disappeared.
하지만, 이름을 알고 있으니
곧 찾을 겁니다
But we got his name.
We'll find him. / Uh oh.
- 왜 그러나?
- 저 차요
- What's up?
- That car.
한쪽 헤드라이트가 깨지지 않았어요
저것만 유일하게 멀쩡하네요
One headlight's not broken.
It's the only one that's not broken.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
집사람이야
It's Karen.
그래, 캐런. 나 일해야 해
이봐, 랜디
Yeah, Karen. I gotta take this.
Hey, Randy.
이 두 사람 그쪽으로 안내하겠나?
Hey, could you fill them in?
여보, 내 메모는 봤어?
Hey. Did you get my note?
세상에나 / 시체는 건드리지 마세요
아직 CSI가 안 왔어요
Oh, my god. / Don't touch the body.
CSI isn't here yet.
- 네, 안 건드릴게요
- 맞아 죽었군
- Okay, I won't touch the body.
- He was bludgeoned.
네, 권총 총열로 맞은 것 같아요
Yeah, looks like with
the barrel of a gun.
이 자국들 보이세요?
See these impressions?
총을 가지고 있었다면
왜 쏘지 않았을까?
If they had a gun,
why didn't they shoot him?
네, 좋은 지적이시네요
Yeah, that is a good question.
이걸 보세요
피해자의 휴대전화입니다
Look at this.
Victim's cell phone.
텅 비어 있어요
Empty.
메모도, 주소록도 없어요
마치 삭제된 것처럼요
No memory, no address book.
Like it's been erased.
전기 충격기로도 그렇게
깨끗이 삭제될 수 있을까?
Could a stun gun do that?
Erase everything?
네, 그럴 수도 있겠죠
Yeah, maybe.
검시관에게 화상 자국이
있는지 살펴보라고 할게요
Yeah, I'll have the coroner
look for burn marks.
전기 충격기라...
Stun gun.
멋진 생각이세요
That's good.
훌륭하세요
You're good.
난 당신 남편이야
왜 나랑 상관이 없겠어
Because I'm your husband
and that makes it my business.
아니, 캐런, 말하기 싫다고?
말해야 할걸
No, Karen, you don't want to talk
about it? You gotta talk about it.
캐런, 아니, 소리 지르는 거 아니야
난 그저...
Karen, No, I'm not yelling.
I'm trying to..
캐런
Karen.
그러시면 안 되죠
좀 잘 대해 주세요
That's not cool, man.
You should treat her better.
- 뭐라고 했나?
- 아, 제 생각에...
What did you say?
Oh, I just..
경감님께서 사모님을 고맙게
여기시지 않는 것 같아서요
I don't really think you
appreciate her.
사모님은... 정말
대단한 분이시잖습니까
She's a..she's a hell of a woman.
- 우리 아는 사이던가?
- 아뇨
- Do I know you?
- No.
그렇지는 않습니다. 중요한 건
경감님이 사모님을 잘 아시냐는 거죠
No, you don't know me. The question
is, do you know your wife?
- 자네 이름이 뭔가?
- 샤키입니다
- What's your name?
- Sharkey, sir.
샤키 경사. 분명 내게
하고 싶은 말이 있는 것 같군
Well, Sgt. Sharkey. You're obviously
trying to tell me something.
지금 내가 우리 집사람에 대해
잘 아느냐고 물어보는 건가?
Are you trying to tell me
that you know my wife?
그런 것 같습니다
Maybe I do.
얼굴에서 웃음을 거두는 게 좋겠군
You'd better wipe that smile
off your face.
그럴 수 있을는지 모르겠습니다
사모님이 주신 웃음이라서요
Well, I don't know if I can do that.
Karen put it there.
자, 자, 진정하세요
Okay.
Hold on.
여기서 다투시면 안 됩니다
여긴 범죄 현장이에요
Hey, you guys, you can't fight here.
This is a crime scene.
저쪽에서 조용히 얘기할까? 가세
You wanna take it down the street?
Let's go.
아, 네. 늘 그런 식으로
만사를 해결하시는군요
Oh, sure, yeah. That's how
you solve everything, isn't it?
화요일 밤에 사모님이 뭘 하는지
궁금해 하신 적 있습니까?
Do you ever wonder what
Karen's doing on Tuesday nights?
경감님이 간부 회의를
하고 계시던 시각에요
You know, when you're
at the staff meeting..
경사, 닥치게. 이건 명령이야
Whoa, Sergeant, shut up.
That's an order.
제 말을 믿으세요
사모님은 경감님께 애정이 식었어요
Take it from me, pal.
She ain't missing you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
알았네. 난 괜찮아, 괜찮네
All right.
I'm okay. It's okay.
괜찮아. 괜찮다니까
Okay, I'm okay.
일단 참으세요
Just walk away from this.
경감님
Captain.
미쳤구먼
뭡니까, 돌았어요?
You maniac.
What, are you kidding.
이가 부러졌잖아, 제길
You knocked my tooth out. God.
대체 왜 이러세요?
What the hell's going on?
저 개자식이 나한테
뭐라고 했는지 아나?
Do you know what that son
of a bitch said to me?
- 미쳤다고 했어요
- 의료반을 부르게
- Maniac.
- Just call the paramedics.
움직이지 마
모두 가만히 있어
Don't move.
Nobody moves.
- 난 집에 가겠네
- 경감님이 이곳 책임자시잖...
- I'm going home.
- Captain, you're in charge..
랜디, 비키게
Randy, get out of my way.
대체 무슨 일이에요?
What the hell happened?
몽크 씨, 어떻게 된 거예요?
Monk, what happened?
모두에게 진술서를 받아야겠군
I'm gonna need statements from everybody.
여보, 이 시간에 웬일이에요?
Leland, what are you doing here?
무슨 일 있었어요?
Did something happen?
질문 한번 잘했군
Now, that's a good question.
무슨 짓을 한 거야?
What did you do?
온도를 높여 놨어?
Did you turn the heat up?
집안이 마치 사우나 같군
It's like a sauna in here.
정확히 37.2도가 되어야 하거든요
Well, it's supposed to be
99 degrees exactly.
기토머 법이라는 건데
건강에 굉장히 도움이 된대요
It's called the Gittomer method.
It's very therapeutic.
숨을 못 쉬겠군
I can't breathe.
손은 왜 그래요?
What happened to your hand?
경관 하나를 팼거든
I punched a cop.
- 경관을 때렸다고요?
- 그래
- You punched a cop?
- Yeah.
라이언 샤키라는 경사야
A sergeant.
Ryan Sharkey.
왜요?
Why?
몰라서 물어?
You don't know?
그놈이 당신이랑
바람을 피웠다고 하던데
He said you and he were
having an affair.
그 말을 믿어요?
여보, 거짓말이에요
And you believed him?
Leland, he is lying.
왜 거짓말을 하겠어, 캐런?
Why would he lie, Karen?
누가 왜 그따위 거짓말을 하냐고?
Why would anybody lie
about something like that?
그거야 나도 모르죠
농담으로 그랬나 보죠
Well, I don't know.
Maybe it was a joke.
그 경찰 유머 같은 거겠죠
"난 네 마누라랑 잤다, 하하하"
You know, cop humor.
I slept with your old lady, ha ha ha.
- 그럼 부인하는 거군
- 아뇨, 부인하는 게 아니라
- So you're denying it.
- No, I'm not denying it.
너무 어처구니가 없어서
반응조차 안 하는 거라고요
It's so crazy I won't even
respond to it.
이런 대화를 하다니
믿기지가 않네요
I can't believe we're even
talking about this.
그게 다 그래서 그랬던 거군
It sure would explain a lot.
- 뭘 그랬다는 거죠?
- 알잖아
- Like what?
- You know.
당신이 사랑방에서 자는 거라든지...
Like you sleeping in the guest room.
그거야 당신이 코를 고니까 그랬죠
Because you've been snoring.
내가 코 고는 게 어디 한두 번이야
I didn't just start snoring, Karen.
게다가 우리 결혼기념일도
잊어버리고...
And you forgetting our anniversary.
이젠 날 더 이상
만지려고도 안 하잖아
And you not wanting to
touch me anymore.
리랜드, 우리 문제 있는 거 맞아요
난 문제가 없다고는 하지 않았어요
Leland, we have problems.
I'm not saying we don't.
하지만, 그런 문제는 아니에요
적어도 바람을 피우지는 않았다고요
But that isn't one of them.
Or at least it wasn't.
예전엔 내 넥타이도 매주곤 했었는데
You used to tie my neckties.
유죄 판결을 받으면, 카르파프는
25년에서 종신형까지도 가능한데
If he's convicted, Michael Karpov
is looking at 25 years to life
그게 살인의 동기로 보입니다
which gives us motive with
a capital m.
카르파프가 가장 유력한
용의자인 셈이죠
That makes him suspect number one.
물증은 있습니까?
What about physical evidence?
불행하게도 충분하지 않습니다
Unfortunately there's not much.
범죄 현장이 두 명의
경찰로 인해 오염되었거든요
Crime scene was contaminated
by two of our own.
하지만, 지금까지는 나쁜 소식이었고
But that's a bad news.
좋은 소식은 목격자가 있다는 겁니다
떠돌이 노숙자죠
The good news is there's a witness,
a homeless man,a transient.
떠돌이 노숙자요
A homeless transient.
제리, 또는 제랄드로 알려졌으며
나이는 35세에서 40세 사이입니다
He's known as Jerry or Gerald.
35, maybe 40 years old.
이 남자를 찾으면 카르파프를
용의자 확인 줄에 세울 수 있습니다
If we can find him, we can bring
Karpov in for a lineup.
고맙네, 경위
지금부턴 내가 맡지
Thank you, lieutenant,
I'll take it from here.
사실은, 경감님
제가 책임자입니다
Actually, sir, I'm in charge.
누가 그래?
Says who?
부서장님께서요
Deputy chief.
정말 죄송합니다
I'm really sorry, sir.
Oh. Um,
계속하게. 난 내 방에 가 있지
carry on, I'll be in my office.
잠시만요, 지시봉을 가져가시죠
Wait, why don't you keep the pointer.
지시봉은 필요 없네, 랜디
잘하고 있군. 계속하게
I don't want the pointer, Randy.
You're doing a great job. Carry on.
아뇨, 괜찮습니다
전 손가락을 쓰면 되거든요
No, no, it's okay.
I can use my finger.
보세요, 이렇게 하면 됩니다
See, works just as well.
더 낫죠. 구부릴 수도 있어요
Even better, it bends.
지시봉 받게, 랜디
Take the pointer, Randy.
자, 일들 합시다
All right, let's get to work.
손 조심하거라. 너무 높잖니
Careful, both your hands, that's too high.
저 놀이기구들은 위험천만해요
제 사견이 아니라 사실이라고요
These things are death traps.
It's not just my opinion. It's a fact.
1952년 벨기에에서 어린아이가
저런 걸 타다가 거의 죽을 뻔했죠
In Belgium, 1952, a kid
almost died on one of those.
- 저기 있군
- 어디요?
- There he is.
- Where?
- 저 남자예요?
- 네
- That guy?
- Yep.
마약상처럼 보이진 않는데요
Doesn't look like a drug dealer.
마약 거래로 두 번이나 기소됐어요
다른 더한 범죄도 저지른 놈이죠
He's indicted for dealing.
He's guilty of a whole lot worse.
카르파프 씨, 안녕하쇼
Mr. Karpov. Good morning.
- Ah.
- Got a minute?
- 시간 좀 있소?
- 경감님께라면 언제든 내드려야죠
Captain Stottlemeyer,
for you any time.
테디, 이분들은 경찰이란다
Teddy.
These men are policemen.
경찰을 보면 어떻게 해야 하지?
What do we do when we
see a policeman?
그래, 아주 잘했다
법을 존중하는 법을 가르치고 있죠
Ah ha, very good. See, I'm teaching
him respect for the law.
- 치클릿이 죽었습니다
- 네, 들었습니다. 슬픈 일이죠
Chicklet has passed on.
Yes, I heard.
Heartbreaking.
꼬마야, 너 거기 뭐가 묻었구나
Hello, you have a little..
You have a smudge there.
- 무슨 생각을 하시는지 압니다, 경감님
- 내가 지워줄게
- I bet I can read your mind, Captain.
- I'll get it.
어제 아침에 내가 어디에
있었는지 궁금하신 거로군요
You wanna know where I was
yesterday morning.
맞습니다. 오전 6시경에요
That's right, about 6 a.m.
6시라면 내 예쁜 아내랑
침대에 있었죠
6 a.m., I was in bed with
my beautiful wife where I belong.
- 증명할 수 있소?
- 그게 중요한 게 아니죠
- Can you prove that?
- That's not the question.
중요한 건 내가 침대에 없었는지
경감님이 증명할 수 있느냐죠
The question is can you
prove I wasn't.
전기 충격기를 가지고
계십니까, 카르파프 씨?
Do you own a stun gun, Mr. Karpov?
내가 그게 왜 필요합니까?
What would I do with a gun?
난 사업가입니다
I'm a businessman.
- 가구를 수입하죠
- 그러시군요
- I import furniture.
- So you do.
아주 아름다우시군요
And you are a very pretty lady.
내가 숙녀 분께 에스토니아 산(産)
탁자나 손수레를 팔면 절 믿으시려나
Perhaps I can sell you endtable,
handcart from Estonia.
Then you would believe me.
보세요, 경찰도 언론도
날 주시하고 있습니다
Look, you're watching me,
the press is watching me.
몰래 그런 짓을 했다면
난 아마 바보일 테죠
I would be a fool to sneak away
and do this thing.
하지만, 난 바보가 아닙니다
And I'm not a fool.
당신이 했거나
누군가에게 시켰겠죠
Either you did it or you
hired somebody to do it.
너도 봤지, 테디?
You see that, Teddy?
저게 바로 소위 억측이라는 거란다
That is what they call speculation.
상대방을 겁주기 위해
경찰들이 하는 수법이지
Somethig that the policemen
do when they're trying to scare you.
가서 네 친구들이랑 놀겠니?
Why don't you go play
with your friends?
목격자가 있습니다, 마이클
There was a witness, Michael.
폐품 처리장에서 모든 걸
목격한 사람이 있어요
A witness at the junkyard.
He saw everything.
- 아, 그 남자가 뭘 봤다던가요?
- 남자요?
- Ah, what did he see?
- He?
목격자가 남자란 걸
어떻게 아셨습니까?
How did you know it was a man?
단지 목격자라고만 말했는데요
He just said a witness.
남잔지 여잔지가 중요한 게 아니죠
어차피 다 허풍 아닙니까
He, she, doesn't hardly matter.
Because you are bluffing.
정말 목격자가 있다면
If you had any witnesses,
난 지금쯤 경찰서의 그 웃기지도 않는
용의자 확인 줄에 서 있을 테니까요
then I would be down at your stationhouse
in one of your ridiculous lineups.
조만간 거기 세워드리겠소
There's gonna be a lineup.
Very soon.
아들이랑 즐거운 시간 보내요, 마이클
Enjoy these moments with
your son, Michael.
사진도 많이 찍고요
Take lots of pictures.
이제 아주 오랫동안
만나기 어려울 테니까요
Because you're not gonna be
seeing him for a very long time.
드디어 멈췄구나
내가 닦아줄게
Finally.
I got it.
토할 것 같아요
I think I'm sick.
네가 알아서 해라
저 아이 폭발한데요
Save yourselves.
She's gonna blow.
끔찍한 일이 벌어질 거예요
It's gonna be ugly.
저기 말이야... 부탁이 있어
캐런이 이따 오후에 나갈 거야
Listen, um, I need a favor.
Karen's going out this afternoon.
영화를 보러 간대
She said she's going to the movies.
- 자네가 집사람을 미행해주게
- 경감님, 안 돼요
I want you to follow her.
Oh, Captain, no.
- 사모님이 전부 부인하셨다면서요?
- 그랬지
- You said she denied everything.
- She did.
경감님, 그 경사가 농담한 거예요
Captain, that sergeant was
joking around.
동료들 앞에서 괜히
으스대고 싶었던 거겠죠
He was just trying to impress
his idiot friends.
내 생각은 달라요
I don't think so.
캐런과 나는...
우린 더 이상 싸우지도 않아
Karen and me,
we don't even fight anymore.
지난주에 나한테는
친구 집에 있다고 그랬는데
Last week, she said she was
at her friend's house.
전화해보니 거기 없더라고
I called her, she wasn't there.
그 일주일 전에도 마찬가지였고
Week before that,
it was the same thing.
경감님, 저한테 그런
부탁은 하지 마세요
Leland, don't ask me to do this.
몽크, 난 정말 알아야겠어
Monk, I really need to know.
내가 직접 할 수도 있지만
I'd do it myself,
그 '분노 조절 수업'인지 뭔지를
들으라고 서장님이 지시하셨어
but the chief says I need
to go to this anger management class
그게 더 열 받아. 난 딱 이 하나
부러뜨렸을 뿐인데 말이야
which really pisses me off.
I knocked out a tooth, one tooth.
그 자식을 죽인 것도 아니잖아
It's not like I killed the guy.
그 이상한 경사는 누구였나요?
처음 보는 사람이었는데
Who was that clown?
I've never seen him before.
라이언 샤키 주니어라고
예전에 오토바이 순찰대였어
Ryan Sharkey Jr.
He was a motorcycle cop.
멘도시노에서 막 전출 온 녀석이야
He just transferred in from Mendocino.
그 친구 인사 기록을 보셨어요?
What, you pulled his file?
당연하지
You bet I did.
아주 유능한 놈이더라고
He's a real hotshot.
큰 건수도 몇 건 올렸고
용감한 경찰관 표창도 두 번이나 받았어
Has a couple of big arrests.
He's been cited for bravery twice.
여자들한테 인기도 엄청 많다더군
And I hear he's a real lady's man.
조언 하나 해드릴까요?
그 사람이 한 말은 잊으세요
You want some advice?
Forget what he said.
그냥 잊으시고 집에 가셔서
사모님이나 안아주세요
Just forget it.
Go home and hug your wife.
조언은 더 이상 필요 없어요
I don't want any more advice.
난 캐런이 오후에 어딜 가는지
알고 싶을 뿐이에요
I wanna know where Karen
is going this afternoon.
사모님한테 들키면요?
경감님이 시켰다고 눈치 채실 텐데요
What if she sees us?
She's gonna know that you
asked us to follow her.
- 그럼 상황이 더 안 좋아지잖아요
- 어디 가는지 모르는 것보다?
Wouldn't that be worse?
Worse than not knowing?
자네도 트루디 사건의 진상을
몰라서 괴로워하고 있잖나?
?? killing you not knowing
what happened to Trudy?
내가 지금까지 자네한테
몇 번이나 부탁을 했지?
How many times have I asked
you for a favor?
103번요. 이것까지
포함하면 104번이네요
103, counting this, 104.
그중에 내가 몇 번이나
"제발"이란 말을 했었나?
How many times have
I said please?
알았어요
Okay.
자, 누군가를 미행하는
법을 알려줄게요
Okay, here's how you follow someone.
적어도 12미터 정도는 떨어져야 해요
Stay at least 40 feet back.
하지만, 18미터 이상 떨어지면 안 되죠
But not more than 60.
그리고 가능하다면 항상
반사물을 이용하도록 해요
And whenever possible, try
to use reflective surfaces.
반사물이라뇨?
Reflective surfaces?
자, 봤죠? 아주 신중하게
반사물을 이용하는 거예요
Yeah, see? Very discreet.
Reflective surfaces.
잠깐, 놓쳤어요
어디로 갔지?
Wait a minute, I lost her.
Where'd she go?
이것도 반사물로 적합하지 않을까요?
Okay, would this be considered
a reflective surfaces?
네, 거울이군요
거울도 괜찮죠
Yeah, well, mirrors.
Mirrors are good, too.
아, 이건 안 좋은데
뭐가 묻은 거지?
Oh, this isn't good.
What is that?
어서요, 어서
Come on, come on, come on.
- 놓치겠어요. 놓친다고요
- 잠깐만요
- She's going, she's going.
- Wait a second.
- 옷깃에 묻은 게 뭐지?
- 어서요
- What is that on my collar?
- Come on.
뭐가 묻은 거야?
What is that?
자, 이리 와요
Okay, come on.
안 돼요, 안 돼
No, no, no, no.
- 정말 못할 짓이에요
- 네, 동감이에요
- I hate this.
- Yeah, I do, too.
두 사람이 결혼한 지 얼마나 됐어요?
How long have they been married?
아주 오래됐죠
캐런과 리랜드...
Forever.
Karen and Leland..
두 사람은 공통점이 한 개도 없었어요
And they never had one thing
in common.
한 번은, 경감님이 주말 동안
사냥을 나간 사이에
I remember, this one weekend,
he went hunting
사모님은 집에서 총기 규제 집회를
준비한 적도 있었어요
and she stayed home
and organized
a rally for stronger gun control.
이른 나이에 결혼하면
어려움이 있는 법이죠
It's hard when people get
married that young, you know.
- 나이를 먹으면 변하게 마련이니까요
- 네, 난 아니지만요
- You get older and change.
- Yeah, not me.
네, 몽크 씨 말고
다른 사람들은 그렇단 얘기죠
Well, I know not you, but people.
- 갑시다
- 가요, 가요
- Come on.
- Go, go, go, go.
미안, 정말 미안해요
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
괜찮아요, 몽크 씨. 어서 가요
It's okay.
Mr. Monk, come on, come on.
- 놓치겠어요
- 그래도 이대로 갈 순 없어요
- She's getting away.
- But you can't just leave her like this.
마네킹이잖아요
It's a mannequin.
그런 식으로 말하면 안 되죠
- Why do you say things like that?
- Oh.
안 되는데
Oh, no.
그래서 그 여자가 좋아하는
레스토랑에 갔어요
So we're at her favorite
restaurant, okay?
그리고 그 한 끼를 위해서
일주일 봉급을 몽땅 썼죠
And I'm spending like a whole week's
paycheck on this one dinner.
그런데 옆 테이블에 있던 자식의
휴대전화가 계속 울리는 거예요
And then this jerk at the table next
to me keeps yapping on his cell phone.
전 휴대전화가 정말 싫어요
I hate those cell phones.
도대체가 진정한 대화를
할 수가 없으니까요
You can't have a decent
conversation anymore.
- 주문은 외웠나요?
- 네, 그럼요
- Did you say your affirmation?
- Yes. Yes, I did. / Uh huh.
네, 노력했습니다. 정말로요
Okay, I tried.
I really did.
조용히 저녁을 즐기고 싶다고
정중히 얘기를 했죠
I said, please, we're trying
to enjoy our dinner.
그랬더니 또 휴대전화가 울리는 거예요
And then his cell phone rang again.
거기서 제가 이성을 잃었나 봐요
And I guess I lost it.
접시를 던졌죠
I threw a plate.
몇 장 던졌어요
A couple of plates.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
네
Yeah.
Uh huh.
지금은 통화하기 곤란해, 여보
나중에 전화할게
Look, I can't talk right now, Karen.
I'll call you later.
리랜드 씨, 전화기를 꺼주시겠어요?
Leland, would you mind
turning that off?
안 됩니다. 근무중이라서요
I can't.
I'm on duty.
당신 뭐 경찰이라도 됩니까?
So what are you, a cop?
맞습니다
That's right.
경찰이라서 나보다 잘났다고 생각해요?
You think you're better than me
because you're a cop?
아뇨, 피터. 공중 예절에 관해선
당신보다 낫다고 생각합니다
No, Peter, I think I'm better
than you on general principle.
뭐, 적어도 난 내 마누라가
어디 있는지는 대충 알죠
Well, at least I have some
rough idea where my wife is.
리랜드, 리랜드. 절 보세요
Leland. Leland, look at me. Look.
절 보세요
Look at me.
그럴 때 어떤 주문을 외라고 했죠?
듣고 싶군요
Say your affirmation.
I wanna hear it.
"그럴 수도 있지"
These things happen.
다시 말해보세요
Say it again.
그럴 수도 있지
These things happen.
앉으세요
Sit down.
그럴 수도 있지
These things happen.
리랜드는 화가 나 있습니다
그게 뭐라고 했죠?
Leland is angry.
Which is what?
- 감정입니다
- 맞습니다
- A feeling.
- That's right.
분노는 감정일 뿐이에요
Anger is just a feeling.
리랜드, 감정대로 행동할
필요는 없습니다
Leland, you don't have to act
on your feelings. You're an adult.
당신은 어른이니 어떻게 대응할지
자신이 선택할 수 있어요
You can choose how you
wanna respond.
맞는 말씀입니다
You're absolutely right.
제가 선물을 하나 드리죠
I'm gonna give you something.
화가 몹시 난 상황에서
주문이 듣지 않을 경우에는
It's a backup plan in case you're
out in the world and you're
in a situation and your affirmation
is not working.
차선책으로 이걸 사용하세요
이건 검증된 거예요
It's a fact.
요요를 하고 있으면
화난 감정이 누그러진답니다
You can't stay mad at anybody
when you're playing with a yo-yo.
이걸 항상 가지고 다니도록 하세요
I want you to take this with you.
전 필요없는대요
I don't think so.
수료증에 제가 서명하지 않으면
You understand if I don't sign
your certificate of completion,
6주간 또 수업을 들으셔야
한다는 걸 아실 텐데요
you're gonna be with us
for another 6 weeks.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
- 기분이 어떠세요?
- 아주 좋군요
- How's that feel?
- It feels great.
- 잘 됐군요
- 고맙습니다
- Good.
- Thank you.
리랜드, 리랜드
그렇게 빨리할 필요는 없어요
Leland, Leland.
You don't have to do it that fast.
전 빨리해야 할 것 같은데요
I guess I do.
전부 확인해봤는데
All right, well, I checked everywhere.
이 상가에는 극장이 없어요
캐런이 거짓말을 했나 봐요
There's no movie theater in this mall,
so she lied about that.
Ah ha.
저기 가네요
몽크 씨, 가야 해요
There she goes.
Mr. Monk, we gotta go.
네, 그러네요
Ha ha, look, yeah.
분수 안에 10달러 3센트가 들었어요
10 dollars and three cents.
That's how much is in there.
그래요, 알려줘서 고마워요
Okay, thank you.
Now we know.
네, 돈을 맞춰야 할 것 같아요
Yeah, I think we should make it even.
무슨 말씀을 하시는 거예요?
What are you talking about?
분수 말이에요
The fountain.
3센트를 빼내면
딱 10달러가 될 거라고요
We take out three cents
and that'll be 10 dollars.
그럼 돈이 딱 맞잖아요
10달러요
It's a nice round number.
10 dollars.
그럼 모두 행복할 거예요
Then everyone would be happier.
항상 그런 말을 하시는데
대체 '모두'가 누구예요?
You always say that.
Who is everyone?
저랑...
Me.
저요
저보고 여기 손을 넣어서
3센트를 집으라고요?
You want me to reach in here
and take out 3 pennies?
- 그렇게 해주면 안 될까요?
- 네, 안 돼요
- Would you mind?
- Yes, I would.
자요, 또 움직이고 있어요
지금 가야해요
Look, look, she's moving again.
We gotta go.
몽크 씨, 일단 가기 시작하면
Mr. Monk, if we walk now,
분수 생각은 안 날 거예요
we won't even think
about the fountain.
생각날 거예요
I'll think about it.
절 계속 따라다닐 거라고요
It would haunt me.
3센트가 초과한 게
계속 따라다닐 거라고요?
The three extra pennies.
It would haunt you?
그럴 거예요
It will haunt me.
자요, 됐죠?
There.
Okay?
좋아요
Okay.
세상에
My god.
정말 누굴 만나고 있네요
She really is seeing somebody.
- 저럴 수가
- 불쌍한 경감님...
- Oh, no.
- No. The poor captain.
저 사람 라이언 샤키인가요?
Is it Ryan Sharkey?
얼굴이 안 보여요
더 가까이 가야겠어요
I can't see his face.
Try to get closer.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
방금 저 분수에서 돈을 꺼내셨나요?
Did you just take money
from that fountain?
아뇨
No.
부인
Ma'am.
네, 그게...
Well, yeah, I mean..
돈을 딱 맞추려던 겁니다
We were making it even.
- 함께 가주셔야겠습니다
- 사진을 찍어야 하는데요
Come with me, please.
I just need to get a shot.
소란 피우고 싶지 않습니다
조용히 따라오세요
I don't want any trouble.
Just come with me.
- 사진 찍어요
- 선생님도 따라오세요
- Get the shots.
- You, too.
사진 찍어요
Get the shots.
겉보기엔 관련 없어 보이던 사실들이
...seemingly unrelated facts
마크의 머릿속에서 명백한
진실로 정리되기 시작했다
coming together in Mark's mind
to form an undeniable truth.
어렴풋했던 사실들이
비로소 명확해지는 순간이었다
A picture of absolute clarity where
before there had been confusion.
"뭘 알고 있지?"
제시가 물었다
What do you know?
Jesse asked him.
"어떻게 윈스턴 브렌트가
살해됐는지 알았어" 마크가 말했다
I know how Winston Brent
was killed, Mark said.
"누가 죽였는지도 알아"
And I know who did it.
말도 안 돼
I cannot believe it.
대체 어떤 변태 자식이 추리소설의
마지막 두 페이지를 찢은 거야?
What kind of degenerate tears out
the last two pages
of a Diagnosis Murder
mystery book?
뭐 하는 겁니까?
What are you doing?
왜 이래요?
저... 절대로 아무 말 안 할게요
약속합니다
I..I..I'm not gonna say anything.
I promise.
미안, 제랄드
Sorry, Gerald.
- 경감님이 왜 전화를 하실까요?
- 받지 말아요
- Why is the Captain calling?
- Don't answer it.
- 계속 피할 순 없어요
- 피할 때까진 피해야죠
- Well, we can't avoid him for ever.
- You've got to try.
제랄드 빙골드 씨?
Gerald Vingold?
안녕하세요, 샌프란시스코
경찰청의 디셔 경위입니다
Hi, I'm Lieutenant Disher,
San Francisco Police.
이쪽은 에이드리안 몽크 씨와
나탈리 티거 씨입니다
This is Adrian Monk,
Natalie Teeger. / Hi.
좀 어떠신가요?
How are you feeling?
3층에서 떨어진 기분이죠, 뭐
Like I got dropped out
of a 3-story window.
다행히도 GE 냉장고의 3중
골판지 박스 위에 떨어졌지만요
Luckily I fell on a triple corrugated
GE refrigerator box.
정말 훌륭한 박스예요
It's an excellent box.
혹시 박스 위에 떨어질 일이 생기면
꼭 GE 3중 골판지를 쓰세요
If you ever fall on a box,
try to make it a GE triple corrugated.
명심하도록 하죠
Well, I'll keep that in mind.
몽크 씨, 질문하세요
Monk, questions?
그래, 그래
빙골드 씨...
Yes. Mr. Vingold, Gerald.
대략 언제쯤이면...
Do you have any idea approximately
지금 씹고 계시는 고기를
다 드실 것 같으신가요?
when you'll be finished chewing
on that piece of meat?
죄송합니다. 진짜 음식다운 음식을
먹어본 지가 너무 오랜만이라서요
Sorry. It's been a long time since
I had a real meal.
저기, 저 좀 여기서 나가게 도와주세요
Listen, you guys gotta help
me get out of here.
괜찮습니다. 여긴 안전합니다
It's okay.
You're perfectly safe.
문밖에 경관 두 명이 지키고 있어요
There's two policemen
stationed right outside the door.
저 때문이 아니에요
디보가 걱정돼서 그럽니다
It's not me.
I'm worried about Devo.
디보가 누구죠?
Who's Devo?
제가 박스 위에 떨어지고 나서
디보가 제 위로 떨어졌죠
I fell on the box
and Devo fell on me.
의사 선생님이 디보를 보시면
무슨 짓을 하실지 몰라요
If the doctors find him,
I don't know what they're gonna do.
병원은 설치류를 싫어하잖아요
아주 질색을 하죠
Hospitals hate rodents.
They're like fanatics about it.
우리가 디보를 돌봐드리겠습니다
We'll take care of Devo
for you, I promise.
정말 귀엽네요
He's actually kinda cute.
나탈리, 만지지 말아요
Natalie, don't touch him.
나중에, 시간이 나면
Later on, when we have time,
내가 흑사병에 대해서
이야기를 해 줄게요
I'll tell you a little story
about the Black Plague.
얘는 보통 쥐가 아니에요
아주 영특하죠. 흉내도 내요
He's not an ordinary mouse.
He's a genius. He does impressions.
디보, 날 봐라. 저블 흉내를 내봐
(Gerbil : 애완용 쥐의 일종)
Watch. Devo, look at me.
Do a gerbil.
해보라니까?
수줍음을 타지만 해낼 거예요
Be a gerbil. He's shy.
But he'll do it.
자, 넌 할 수 있어
그래, 어서, 할 수 있어
Come on, boy, you can do it.
Yeah, go on, you can do it.
저블 흉내 내봐
Do the gerbil.
아, 했어요
보셨어요?
Ah, there it is.
Did you see that?
네, 엄청나네요
로버트 드니로 같아요
Yeah. It's uncanny.
He's like Robert DeNiro.
빙골드 씨, 목에 화상 자국이
두 군데 나 있는데
Yeah, um, Mr.Vingold,
those two burnmarks
on your neck, did he attack you
with a stun gun? / Yes, sir.
범인이 전기 충격기로
공격을 했습니까? / 네
- 범인을 확실히 보셨고요?
- 그럼요
- And you got a good look at him?
- I sure did.
죽을 때까지 그 얼굴 못 잊습니다
제가 마흔 살까지 살는지는 모르겠지만
I'll never forget that face
if I live to be 40.
그리고 전에 폐품 처리장에서
본 사람과 동일인이 확실하고요?
And you're sure it was the same guy
that you saw before in the junk yard?
확실합니다. 같은 사람이에요
Definitely.
The same guy.
빙골드 씨, 범인이라고
짐작되는 사람이 있습니다
Mr.Vingold, we think
we know who did this.
마이클 카르파프라는 사람인데요
His name is Michael Karpov.
이따가 경찰서에 모시고 갈 테니
I'd like to bring you down
to the station house later today,
용의자 확인 줄에서 그자를
확인해주실 수 있을까요?
so you can take a good look at him.
We'll set a lineup.
빙골드 씨, 좀 어떠신가요?
Mr.Vingold, how are we feeling today?
이거 다 드셨죠?
You finished with this?
자, 이제 맥박을 잴게요
Right, I'm gonna take your pulse.
죄송합니다만, 여러분
면회 시간은 끝났습니다
I'm sorry, golks,
but visiting hours are over.
- 휴식을 취하셔야 해요
- 고맙습니다
- He needs his rest.
- Thank you.
- 괜찮으세요?
- 괜찮아요
- Are you okay?
- Fine.
어깨가 좀 쑤셔서요
My shoulder's a little sore.
빙골드 씨, 이것 좀요
Mr.Vingold, good to see you.
- 소각로 -
- 경감님
- 왔어요?
- Captain.
- Hey.
하루종일 전화했었는데
내 전화를 피한 건가요?
I've been calling you guys all day.
Have you been avoiding me?
네, 피했어요
Yes, we have.
이 사진을 현상하느라
기다리고 있었거든요
We were waiting till we could
print this for you.
누군가를 만나고 있었군
She's seeing somebody.
그럴 줄 알았어
I knew it.
- 이게 누군가?
- 얼굴은 못 봤습니다
Who is it?
We never saw his face.
이게 찍은 거 다란 말이야?
Is this any way to photograph a guy?
- 저희가 체포를 좀 당하느라고요
- 좀 황당한 일이 있었죠
- We sort of got arrested.
- It's a funny story.
- 난 듣고 싶지 않네
- 아뇨, 정말 웃긴 얘기예요
- I don't wanna hear it.
- No, it's really funny.
정말 듣고 싶지 않네
I really don't wanna hear it.
- 이 자식 샤키 맞지?
- 아닌 것 같아요
- It's Sharkey, isn't it?
- I don't think so.
저 사람 왼쪽 귀를 보시면 알겠지만...
If you look at the shape of
his left ear..
난 귀 생김새 얘기 따윈
듣고 싶지 않아!
I don't wanna hear about
the shape of the man's ear.
몽크, 그 자식이야
확실해
Monk, it's him.
I can tell.
그럴 수도 있지
These things happen.
그럴 수도 있어
제기랄
Screw it.
5분 후에 아래층에서 용의자 확인을
할 건데, 쪽수를 채워야 한다
Guys, I've got a lineup downstairs
in 5 minutes. I need to fill it out.
자원자 있나?
Volenteers?
좋아
Fine.
- 리차드, 키가 얼마나 되지?
- 178입니다
- Richard, how tall are you?
- Five ten.
좋아, 지원을 받아 주지
1번이야
Good, you just volunteered.
You're one.
카르파프 씨, 당신은 2번입니다
Mr. Karpov, you're two.
법원 명령 따윈 필요 없습니다
이건 시간 낭비라고요
I don't need your court order.
You're just wasting everybody's time.
두고 보면 알겠죠
We will see.
- 랜더우, 자네가 3번이야
- 저는 안 됩니까?
- Landau, you're three.
- What's wrong with me?
미안, 자넨... 키가 너무 작아
Sorry. You're too short.
재밌군, 재밌어
It's funny.
놀티, 자넨 4번이야
한 명 더 필요하다
Nolte, you're four.
I need one more.
샤키, 자네가 하게
5번이야
Sharkey, you're in the lineup.
You're five.
전 빼주세요, 경위님
막 교대 근무 끝났다고요
Not me, lieutenant.
I just finished the double shift.
부탁하는 게 아니야
I'm not asking you.
자, 가지
다들 가자고
All right, let's go.
Let's do this.
어서
Come on.
제랄드, 이쪽은 검찰에서 나오신
호프만 씨입니다
Gerald, this is Mr. Hoffman
from the District Attorney's office.
긴장하지 마세요
Just relax.
이건 반거울이라
저쪽에선 여길 못 봅니다
It's one-way glass.
They won't even know you're here.
- 준비되셨어요?
- 네
- Ready?
- Yeah.
자, 들여보내
Okay, send them in.
저, 저 사람이에요
저 사람이 범인이에요
That..that's him.
That's the guy.
너도 알아보겠지, 디보?
You recognize him,
don't you, Devo?
- 저 사람이...
- 잠깐만요
- He..he's...
- W..wait.
아무 말씀 하지 마세요
절차대로 진행해야 합니다
Don't say anything.
We have to do this by the book.
각자 앞으로 나올 때까지
기다려야 합니다
We have to wait till
they all step forward.
라이언 샤키 어디 있는지 아나?
You know where Ryan Sharkey's at?
아래층 용의자 확인실에 있습니다
He's downstairs in the lineup.
2번, 앞으로 나와 주세요
Number two, step forward.
왼쪽으로 돌아 주세요
Turn to your left.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
3번, 앞으로 나와 주세요
Number three, step forward.
- 이거 네놈이지?
- 참 딱하십니다
- Is that you?
- You're pathetic.
고맙습니다
4번, 앞으로 나와 주세요
Thank you.
Number four, step forward.
3번, 요요는 집어넣어 주세요
Number three, please put the yo-yo away.
4번, 오른쪽으로 돌아 주세요
Number four, turn to your right.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
- 대체 문제가 뭡니까?
- 네놈이 내 문제다!
- What's your problem?
- You're my problem.
4번, 3번을 놓아주세요
Number four, please let go
of number three.
5번, 발로 차지 말아 주세요
Number five, stop kicking.
2번, 앞으로 나와 주세요
Number two, step forward.
3번, 4번을 놓아주시고
앞으로 나와 주세요
Number three, please let go
of number four. Step forward.
- 어떻게 되어가나?
- 그만 하세요. 그만들 하세요
How's it going?
Please stop.
Stop. Stop please.
3번을 놓아주세요
Please let go of number three.
잠깐요, 저기 있어요
범인이 저기 있다고요
Wait, he's in there.
The killer in there.
분명 있겠죠, 빙골드 씨
하지만, 상관없습니다
I'm sure he is, Mr. Vingold.
But it doesn't matter.
다 망쳤어요
The lineup is busted.
이건 경찰 역사상 최악의
용의자 확인이 분명할 겁니다
That might have been the worst lineup
in the history of law enforcement.
그래, 교범대로 진행되진 않았지
Yeah, it wasn't exactly textbook,
was it.
- 경감님, 어떻게 해야 하죠?
- 정석대로 하게, 랜디
Captain, what should I do?
You do your job, Randy.
있었던 일 그대로 기록해
내 걱정은 말고
You write it up exactly as it happened.
Don't worry about me.
카르파프는 어디 있나?
Where's Karpov?
풀어줘야 했습니다
We had to let him go.
경사, 앉아 있게!
Sergeant, sit down.
자네한테도 진술서를 받아야 하니까
We're gonna need a statement
from you too.
여보, 나탈리가 전화해서
당신이 또 싸웠다고 하더군요
Leland, Natalie called to tell me
that you've been fighting again.
괜찮아요?
Are you okay?
그래, 난 괜찮아
Yeah, I'm okay.
당신 남자친구한테도 물어보지그래?
Why don't you ask about
your boyfriend?
안녕하세요, 캐런
Hey, Karen.
리랜드, 난 저 사람 생전 처음 봐요
Leland, I've never seen that
man before in my life.
여보, 이제 연기 안 해도 돼
Karen, you can just stop pretending.
그건 날 모욕하는 거야
Now you're just insulting me.
캐런, 당신이 말 좀 해주실래요?
Karen, would you just tell him?
리랜드, 날 죽이고 싶어 하는 거 압니다
Leland, I know you want to kill me.
저라도 똑같이 느꼈을 거예요
I'd probably feel the same way,
all right?
하지만, 이해해 주세요
But you gotta understand.
캐런과 저 사이에 있었던 일은
아무런 의미도 없습니다
Whatever happened between Karen
and I didn't mean anything.
아셨어요? 그냥 실수였습니다
All right?
It was a mistake.
죄송합니다
제가 사과드릴게요
I'm sorry.
I'm apologizing to you.
너 뭐야?
Who are you?
여보, 이 사람 미친 게 분명해요
Leland, he must be crazy.
캐런, 재밌긴 하지만
자기 행동에 책임을 지셔야죠
Karen, it was fun.
You gotta face the music.
우리 사이는 끝났어요, 아셨어요?
It's over between us.
Okay?
나 이 사람 몰라요
내 말을 믿어야 해요
Okay, I don't know him.
You've got to believe me.
- 그래야 한다고?
- 네, 그래야 해요
- Do I?
- Yes, you do.
- 당신은 날 믿어야 해요
- 왜 저놈이...
- You have to believe me.
- Why would he..
왜 저놈이 거짓말을 하겠어, 캐런?
왜 저런 말을 지껄이느냐고?
Why would he lie, Karen?
Why would he say these things?
잠깐만요
실례합니다, 경사
Excuse me.
Excuse me, sergeant.
지금 사과를 왼쪽으로 씹고 있군요
You're chewing that apple
on your left side.
- 네, 그런데요?
- 왜죠?
- Yeah, so?
- Why?
당신 친구가 이틀 전에 내 이를
부러뜨렸잖아요. 기억나세요?
Why, because your friend knocked
my tooth out two day ago, remember?
네, 기억납니다
Yes, I remember.
하지만, 이쪽으로 맞은 게 아닌데요
But he didn't hit you
on this side.
경감님은 오른손잡이입니다
The captain is right-handed.
반대쪽 얼굴을 때렸죠
당신 왼쪽 얼굴을요
He hit you on the other side.
Your left side.
- 지금... 당신이 씹고 있는 쪽을요
- 그런데요?
The side..the side you're
chewing on. / Okay.
당신 이를 부러뜨린 건
경감님이 아닙니다, 그렇죠?
The captain didn't knock
your tooth out, did he?
- 당신 뭐요? 미쳤어요?
- 이제 다른 것도 기억이 나는군요
What are you, crazy?
I'm remembering a few other things.
당신은... 멘도시노에서
근무했어요, 그렇죠?
You..you used to work
at Mendocino, right?
우리가 마이클 카르파프를
공원에서 만났을 때
When we saw Michael Karpov
in the park,
그 사람 아들이 입고 있던 셔츠에
멘도시노 학교라고 쓰여 있었어요
his son was wearing a shirt.
It said Mendocino Day School.
- 마이클 카르파프가 멘도시노에 살죠
- 네, 많은 사람들이 멘도시노에 살죠
Michael Karpov lives in Mendocino.
Yeah, a lot of people live in Mendocino.
난 마이클 카르파프를 모릅니다
I don't know Michael Karpov.
알 텐데요
10분 전, 아래층에서
I think you do.
Ten minutes ago, downstairs,
당신은 지금처럼 사복 차림이었는데
카르파프가 당신을 경사라고 불렀어요
you were wearing those clothes
and Karpov called you sergeant.
맞아요. 저도 들었어요
That's right.
I heard that too.
당신이 경사란 걸 그 사람이
어떻게 알았을까요, 경사?
How did he know
you were sergeant, Sergeant?
디셔 경위다. 제랄드 빙골드 씨가
아직 건물 안에 있나?
This is Disher. Is Gerald Vingold
still in the building?
당신은 마이클 카르파프를
위해 일했어요
You work for Michael Karpov.
우리도 그놈 수하 중에
경찰이 있을 거라고 의심했었지
We always suspected
there was a cop on his payroll.
당신이 치클릿을 죽였죠?
You killed Chicklet, didn't you?
그래서 총으로 죽이지 않은 거예요
That's why you didn't shoot him.
당신 권총으로 추적되리라는 걸
알고 있었으니까요
Cuz you knew the bullet could be
traced back to your weapon.
사건은 이렇게 된 겁니다
Here's what happened.
당신은 치클릿을
폐품 처리장으로 불러냈어요
You lured Chicklet
to the junk yard.
하지만, 치클릿은 반항을 했죠
But he fought back.
당신은 맞아서 피를 흘렸을 겁니다
He must've hit you.
You were bleeding.
이도 부러졌어요
큰 골칫거리가 생긴 거죠
You lost a tooth.
And you had a big problem.
당신의 DNA가 사건 현장에
온통 널려 있었으니까요
Your DNA was all over
that crime scene.
경찰도 오고 있었기 때문에
현장을 처리할 시간이 없었어요
And the cops were on the way.
You didn't have time
to clean it up.
당신은 제복으로 갈아입고
다시 사건 현장으로 왔습니다
You put your uniform on.
You returned to the scene.
하지만, 곧 감식반이
도착하리란 걸 알았어요
But you knew forensics would
be there any minute.
어떻게 하지?
What to do?
어떡할까?
그때 좋은 수가 생각났어요
What to do?
Then you had an idea.
난 당신 남편이야
왜 나랑 상관이 없겠어?
I'm your husband.
That makes it my business, okay?
만약 누군가와 싸움이 벌어진다면
If you picked a fight with someone,
만약 상대를 자극해서
당신을 때리게 한다면
if you could provoke them
and get them to hit you,
당신 고민은 해결되는 거죠
you'd be home free.
당신의 이와 DNA, 혈흔이
발견된다고 해도...
They could find your tooth,
your DNA, your blood.
아무도 의심을 품지 않을 테니까요
And nobody would ever question it.
우리 남편한테 얻어맞기 위해
나랑 잤다고 거짓말을 했다고?
You told my husband we were
sleeping together so that he would hit you?
무슨 말이에요
아무것도 증명할 수 없을걸요
???
You can't prove any of this.
할 수 있어. 네놈과 카르파프를
연결할 수 있어
I think we can.
We can connect you to Karpov.
네 전화 기록, 이메일
은행 계좌를 뽑아볼 거야
We'll pull your phone bills,
your e-mails, your bank accounts.
네, 그것보다는 좀 더
그럴듯한 게 필요할걸요
Yeah, I think you might need
a little more than that.
저 사람이에요
내가 종일 말했잖아요
That's the guy.
I've been telling you guys all day.
폐품 처리장에서 본 사람이
바로 저 사람이라고요
I saw him at the junk yard.
That's the guy.
아, 저기...
이거 다 먹은 겁니까?
Oh, hey, are you done with that?
제가 먹으려는 게 아니에요
It's not for me.
디보한테 주려고요
It's for Devo.
이 녀석도 아주 힘든 하루를 보냈거든요
He's had a pretty rough day.
저 쥐가 내 주머니에 있었어
내 주머니에 있었다고!
That mouse was in my pocket.
It was in my pocket.
가지, 샤키
Let's go, Sharkey.
괜찮아?
Are you okay?
아주 혼이 났지?
Heck of a thing, huh?
사실, 이렇게 생각해주면 좋겠어
Actually, it's kind of flattering
if you think about it.
저놈이 날 택한 건 내가
반응할 걸 알았기 때문이라고
He picked me because
he knew that I would react.
내가 당신을 얼마나 사랑하는지
알았기 때문이라고 말이야
Cuz he could tell how much
I love you.
좋게 생각되지 않네요, 리랜드
It's not flattering, Leland.
여보, 그동안 성질 부렸던 거
나도 알아
Look, Karen.
I know that I've got a temper,
하지만, 나도 노력 중이야
but I've been working on it.
나 요요도 있어
I've got a yo-yo.
사실은... 그 녀석한테 던져서
박살났지만 말이야
Actually, I, uh, the yo-yo broke
when I threw it at the guy.
왜 날 믿지 않았죠?
Why didn't you believe me?
어제 오후에 몽크한테
당신을 미행하라고 했어
I had Monk follow you
yesterday afternoon.
당신이 어떤 남자랑
만나는 걸 봤다더군
He saw you meeting a man.
날 미행하라고 시켰다고요?
You had me followed?
뭐 하고 싶은 말 없어?
You wanna tell me about it?
이 사람 이름은 맥스 테퍼톤이에요
His name is Max Tepperton.
이혼 전문 변호사죠
He's a divorce lawyer.
이혼 전문 변호사랑
바람을 피웠던 거야?
You've been sleeping
with a divorce lawyer?
뭐 아무래도 좋아
You know what?
It doesn't matter.
난 당신을 용서하니까, 캐런
Because I forgive you, Karen.
내가 성자는 아니지만
Hell, I'm no saint.
- 우린 극복할 수 있을 거야
- 아뇨, 리랜드
- We'll get past this.
- No, Leland.
그 사람은 내 대리인이에요
He's representing me.
스토틀마이어 대 스토틀마이어
Stottlemeyer vs. Stottlemeyer.
이유가 뭐지? / 당신은 그 이유조차
모르고 있기 때문이에요, 리랜드
Why? / Because you have
to ask why, Leland.
그게 이유죠
That's why.
이게 다예요?
So is that it?
네
Yep.
결혼 생활 20년에 가방 두 개...
Twenty years, two suitcases.
아이들은 어디 갔어요?
Where are the boys?
캐런과 함께 있어요
They're with Karen.
아이들 이모네 집에요
At her sister's.
아이들은 어때요?
How are they doing?
좋지 않죠
Not good.
경감님, 혹시 대화 상대가 필요하시면
Listen, captain, if you need
somebody to talk to,
언제든 무슨 일이든 전화하세요
한밤중이라도 상관없어요
just call, anytime about anything
even in the middle of the night.
몽크, 자네 전화번호는 아네
Monk, I know your number.
아뇨, 이건 제 전화가 아니에요
나탈리의 집 전화번호예요
No, no, it's not me.
It's Natalie's home phone.
정말 상담 솜씨가 좋거든요
She's really good.
맞아요. 언제든 전화하세요
He's right.
Anytime.
고마워요
Thank you.
이런 속담 아시죠
"신은 문 한쪽을 닫을 때면..."
Well, you know the old saying,
"When God closes a door..."
신은 문 한쪽을 닫을 때면
When God closes a door,
때때로 사람 마음을 찢어놓는다
sometimes He breaks your heart.
그건 속담이랑은 다른데요
That's not the old saying.
요즘은 바뀌었어요
It is today.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)